Shanshan Pan

(+086)13335765163 | psshappystar@gmail.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am interested in Computer Graphics and Computer Vision, with a particular focus on **structural analysis and reconstruction** of 3D models. My current research focuses on utilizing **geometric primitives** for model simplification and Level of Detail (LOD) generation, integrating both **traditional assembly techniques** and **neural optimization approaches** (e.g., 3DGS). Additionally, I am deeply interested in **generative 3D shape synthesis**, exploring innovative methods for automatic shape creation and manipulation.

EDUCATION

Zhejiang Taizhou High School

Sep 2014 - Jun 2017

High School

Taizhou, China

- National College Entrance Examination: 628 / 750
- · Editor-in-Chief, High School Journalism Club

Xidian University Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

Software engineering, Bachelor

Xian, China

- GPA: 3.80 / 4.00
- Thesis: "3D Simplified Reconstruction Algorithm for Urban Architecture"
- · Supervisors: Prof. Hui Huang and Prof. Huimin Qin

Shenzhen University Sep 2021 - Jun 2024

Computer Science and Software Engineering, Master

Shenzhen, China

- GPA: 3.33 / 4.00
- Thesis: "Structural Analysis and Reconstruction for Urban Scenes"
- · Supervisor: Prof. Hui Huang

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Visual Computing Research Center, Shenzhen University

Jul 2024 - Present

Research Assistant

- Shenzhen, China
- Lead a 3DGS-related project, proposing an innovative visual-guided surface reconstruction method.
- Provide mentorship to junior team members, fostering a collaborative research environment.

HONORS & AWARDS

The Second Prize Scholarship, Shenzhen University

2022,2023

The First Prize Scholarship, Xidian University

2018,2019,2020

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

3D Structure-aware Reconstruction (Published)

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021

First author, Visual Computing Research Center (VCC), SZU

- Propose an efficient and robust 3D simplified reconstruction algorithm, assembling planar primitives to generate concise polygonal meshes.
- Shanshan Pan, Jiahui Lv, Hao Fang and Hui Huang. Efficient and robust 3D structure-aware reconstruction. Journal of Image and Graphics.

First author, Visual Computing Research Center (VCC), SZU

• Propose a structure-aware analysis of planar primitives to identify the 3D architectural structures and construct a reasonable LOD-Tree to generate semantic-aware LOD models.

Architectural Co-LOD Generation (Published)

Oct 2023 - May 2024

Second author, Visual Computing Research Center (VCC), SZU

- Introduce shape co-analysis to standardize geometric structures across multiple buildings, facilitating the progressive and consistent generation of LODs.
- Runze Zhang, **Shanshan Pan**, Chenlei Lv, Minglun Gong and Hui Huang. Architectural Co-LOD Generation. ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG), 2024, 43(6): 1-16.

B-Reps Construction of 3D CAD Models (Published)

Oct 2023 - Jan 2024

Third author, Visual Computing Research Center (VCC), SZU

- Propose a novel method for predicting a Voronoi Diagram that explicitly reveals both the number of primitives and their connections, along with a "fit" operation to derive a single primitive within each Voronoi Cell, enabling the construction of B-Reps for 3D CAD models.
- Yilin Liu, Jiale Chen, **Shanshan Pan**, Daniel Cohen-Or, Hao Zhang and Hui Huang. Split-and-fit: Learning b-reps via structure-aware voronoi partitioning. ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG), 2024, 43(4): 1-13.

Structural Gaussian Splatting (On going)

May 2024 - Present

Project Leader, Visual Computing Research Center (VCC), SZU

• The goal is to incorporate additional structural information into Gaussian primitives, enabling them to not only achieve high-quality rendering but also facilitate the direct extraction of structured 3D models.

MISCELLANEOUS

Skills: C++, Python, Latex, Adobe Illustrator

• Languages: IELTS 6.5

• Interests: Drawing and Writing, Badminton and Tennis

• Activities: Organize a paper-sharing group among classmates